<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on Pao Corrales</title>
    <link>/categories/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on Pao Corrales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(In review) Hourly Assimilation of Different Sources of Observations Including Satellite Radiances in a  Mesoscale Convective System Case During RELAMPAGO campaign</title>
      <link>/publications/hourly-assimilation-of-different-sources-of-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/hourly-assimilation-of-different-sources-of-observations/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In this paper, we evaluate the impact of assimilating high-resolution surface networks and satellite observations using the WRF-GSI-LETKF over central and north eastern Argentina where the surface and upper air observing networks are relatively coarse. We conducted a case study corresponding to a huge mesoscale convective system (MCS) that developed during November 22, 2018. The accumulated precipitation associated with this MCS was quite high, exceeding 200 mm over northern Argentina and Paraguay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</title>
      <link>/courses/reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/reproducibility/</guid>
      <description>With considerable effort, you wrote R code to analyze your data and generate a final document or report to present the results. You then give the code to a colleague for them to evaluate it, they don’t know which packages they need to install, they don’t have the necessary data and they don’t know if the correct script is report_final.Rmd or report_final_final.Rmd. Even after your guidance, they find that the code does not run on their machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A rapid refresh ensemble based data assimilation and forecast system for the RELAMPAGO field campaign</title>
      <link>/publications/rrr-for-relampago/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/rrr-for-relampago/</guid>
      <description>Highlights
 A LETKF-WRF system was run successfully in real-time to support RELAMPAGO operations. A reduction in forecast error was shown due to data assimilation cycles. 60-member RRR analyses and forecasts are available for the research community.  Abstract This paper describes the lessons learned from the implementation of a regional ensemble data assimilation and forecast system during the intensive observing period of the Remote sensing of Electrification, Lightning, And Mesoscale/microscale Processes with Adaptive Ground Observations (RELAMPAGO) field campaign (central Argentina, November–December 2018).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Spreadsheets to R</title>
      <link>/courses/fromspreadsheettor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/fromspreadsheettor/</guid>
      <description>This course is intended for people who use spreadsheets for data manipulation and have never programmed, but would like to learn how to work with R. Therefore its starts from the beginning: why use R? and where to start?
We propose to work with R in an orderly and reproducible way. For this reason, we present a workflow that allows those who take this course to apply good programming practices, work collaboratively and present their work in a single document that includes the analysis and the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Parameterization of the Cloud Scattering Polarization Signal Derived From GPM Observations for Microwave Fast Radative Transfer Models</title>
      <link>/publications/parameterization-of-the-cloud-scattering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/parameterization-of-the-cloud-scattering/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Microwave cloud polarized observations have shown the potential to improve precipitation retrievals since they are linked to the orientation and shape of ice habits. Stratiform clouds show larger brightness temperature (TB) polarization differences (PDs), defined as the vertically polarized TB (TBV) minus the horizontally polarized TB (TBH), with ~10 K PD values at 89 GHz due to the presence of horizontally aligned snowflakes, while convective regions show smaller PD signals, as graupel and/or hail in the updraft tend to become randomly oriented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uso de R en Latinoamérica, fortalezas, desafíos y debilidades</title>
      <link>/talk/survey-user2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/survey-user2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching to teach without losing anyone along the way</title>
      <link>/talk/metatodencia-user2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/metatodencia-user2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assimilation of conventional and satellite observations in a deep convection case during RELAMPAGO using the WRF-GSI-LETFK system</title>
      <link>/talk/norce2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/norce2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carpentries</title>
      <link>/project/thecarpentries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/thecarpentries/</guid>
      <description>About The Carpentries     Vision: Our vision is to be the leading inclusive community teaching data and coding skills.
Mission: The Carpentries builds global capacity in essential data and computational skills for conducting efficient, open, and reproducible research. We train and foster an active, inclusive, diverse community of learners and instructors that promotes and models the importance of software and data in research. We collaboratively develop openly-available lessons and deliver these lessons using evidence-based teaching practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RLadies</title>
      <link>/project/rladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/rladies/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies is a worldwide organization whose mission is to promote gender diversity in the R community.
The R community suffers from an underrepresentation of minority genders (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender) in every role and area of participation, whether as leaders, package developers, conference speakers, conference participants, educators, or users ( see recent stats).
As a diversity initiative, the mission of R-Ladies is to achieve proportionate representation by encouraging, inspiring, and empowering people of genders currently underrepresented in the R community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
