<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Pao Corrales</title>
    <link>/categories/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Pao Corrales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gestión de Datos</title>
      <link>/courses/gestion_datos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/gestion_datos/</guid>
      <description>Español     Materia 186 - Gestión de Datos     Ante la necesidad de cualquier persona que practique la ciencia de datos de manipular distintos volúmenes de datos, la gestión de los mismos cobra gran importancia. En esta materia abordaremos el tema de la gestión de datos desde el punto de vista teórico y práctico, incluyendo estudios de casos y actividades para brindarles las herramientas necesarias para continuar con su formación.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rOpenSci</title>
      <link>/project/thecarpentries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/thecarpentries/</guid>
      <description>About rOpenSci     rOpenSci fosters a culture that values open and reproducible research using shared data and reusable software
My role in the community     I&amp;rsquo;m part of the Multilingual Publishing Project, as a reviewer of the Dev Guide translations project to Spanish. I&amp;rsquo;m also one of the authors of the rOpenSci Localization and Translation Guidelines, that explains all the steps and tools involved in the localization of rOpenSci&amp;rsquo;s materials, including translations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generando tutoriales interactivos con el paquete {learnr}</title>
      <link>/courses/tutorialesinteractivos_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/tutorialesinteractivos_intro/</guid>
      <description>Español     Objetivos     El objetivo de este curso es introducir a las personas que participan al paquete {learnr} de R y como utilizarlo para generar tutoriales interactivos que permitan a los y las estudiantes escribir y ejecutar código R directamente desde el tutorial, contestar preguntas y recibir feedback inmediato.
¿Para quién está pensado este taller?     Cada lección debe ser pensada, organizada y generada para una audiencia en particular, estas son las personas tipo en la que pensamos cuando preparamos este taller:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cómo enseñar a programar online</title>
      <link>/courses/teach_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/teach_programming/</guid>
      <description>Español - Cómo enseñar a programar online     Objetivos     Introducir técnicas y buenas prácticas para diseñar tus cursos de programación y evaluar a tus estudiantes.
Durante este taller remoto:
  Mostraremos cómo diseñar tus cursos de programación de una manera eficiente y productiva.
  Hablaremos de la utilidad de la revisión entre pares y la importancia de recibir feedback. Discutiremos cómo implementar estas prácticas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RForwards</title>
      <link>/project/rforwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/rforwards/</guid>
      <description>About RForwards     The task force was set up by the R Foundation in December 2015 to address the underrepresentation of women and rebranded in January 2017 to accommodate more under-represented groups such as LGBT, minority ethnic groups, and people with disabilities in the R community.
The members of the task force were invited to participate based on their interest in routing for specific under-represented groups and their contributions in the area of diversity and inclusion, to reflect different genders, ethnic groups, work contexts, career stages and aspects of the R project (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetaDocencia</title>
      <link>/project/metadocencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/metadocencia/</guid>
      <description>Soy co-fundadora de MetaDocencia y hasta Mayo de 2022 fui parte del core team. Durante estos 2 años ayudé en el desarrollo de materiales y nuevos cursos, colaboré en la traducción de otros materiales, co-coordiné la infraestructura de la comunidad y coordiné el equipo de código de conducta.
Sobre MetaDocencia hasta Mayo 2022     Nuestra visión     Somos una comunidad inclusiva y colaborativa que mejora la educación potenciando docentes de países menos favorecidos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carpentries</title>
      <link>/project/ropensci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ropensci/</guid>
      <description>About The Carpentries     Vision: Our vision is to be the leading inclusive community teaching data and coding skills.
Mission: The Carpentries builds global capacity in essential data and computational skills for conducting efficient, open, and reproducible research. We train and foster an active, inclusive, diverse community of learners and instructors that promotes and models the importance of software and data in research. We collaboratively develop openly-available lessons and deliver these lessons using evidence-based teaching practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RLadies</title>
      <link>/project/rladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/rladies/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies is a worldwide organization whose mission is to promote gender diversity in the R community.
The R community suffers from an underrepresentation of minority genders (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender) in every role and area of participation, whether as leaders, package developers, conference speakers, conference participants, educators, or users ( see recent stats).
As a diversity initiative, the mission of R-Ladies is to achieve proportionate representation by encouraging, inspiring, and empowering people of genders currently underrepresented in the R community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
